Personal info

Name: Yajie (Cathy) Guan

Address: Research School of Physics, Australian National University

60 Mills Rd, Acton ACT 2601, Australia

Phone: (+61) 451026951 E-mail: yajie.guan@anu.edu.au

Personal Website: https://yajieguan.github.io

Citizenship: Australia (Eligible for E3 Visa)

Language: Chinese (Native); English (Proficiency, IELTS [8/9])

Professional Summary

Self-directed and motivated PhD Student from ANU Centre for Gravitational Astrophysics with research background of photonics sensing and laser stabilization. Involved in multiple research projects, including cavity enhanced spectroscopy and fibre array sensing. Having a broad knowledge in applied optics, from physics point of view (including free space optics, optical resonator, fibre, lasers, etc) to engineering prototyping (from software programming to hardware analog design). Demonstrated ability to work in a challenging and fast-paced environment. Having two years of experience in a start-up company working on industrial projects and volume production, especially in charge of hardware design and associated QA/QC test development. Recognized as a strong collaborator with ability of efficient communication with third-party manufacturers (domestic and international). Skilled at multiple programming languages and interested in learning state-of-the-art techniques (such as machine learning algorithms) and utilizing it to solve problems in different projects.

Personal skills

Programming C/C++; Matlab; Python; Verilog; Hardware Description Language (HDL); Languages

SoftwareVisual Studio; Vivado; Vitis; LTspice; Labview;

Multiphysics Coupling and Analysis (Comsol); Optical Waveguide Simulation Software (RSoft); Machine Learning tools (Pytorch, scikit-learn);

AutoDesk; Solidwork;

Optical free-space optics handling (lens, PBS, waveplates, etc.); skills

optical fibre handling (stripping, splicing, etc.);

free-space cavity design and alignment; cavity mode calculation and modeling; laser mode matching; laser stabilization; polarization analysis and simulation;

optical equipment handling (spectrometers, detectors, EOM, OTDR, etc.);

Electronic PID control system design and analysis;

skillselectronic circuit simulation;

> analog system design and testing (ADC, DAC, trigger, etc.); digital system design and testing (SoC, WiFi, USB, etc.);

electronic devices handling (oscilloscope, spectrum analyser, probes, etc.);

Research Projects

| Free-space optic sensing | |
|--|-------------|
| Cavity Enhanced Laser Absorption Spectroscopy | 2015 - 2020 |
| Acoustic sensing using optical interferometry | 2018 - 2019 |
| Optical fibre array sensing | |
| Lead fiber noise reduction using time-delay interferometry | 2013 - 2014 |
| Education | |
| Australian National University | 2015 - 2021 |
| Doctor of Philosophy in Physics (Photonics) | |
| • Advisor: Professor. Jong Chow | |
| • Thesis title: Novel cavity - enhanced techniques for metrology | |
| Australian National University | 2012 - 2014 |
| Bachelor of Engineering with First Class Honors | |
| • Major: Electronic and Communications. | |
| • Minor: Physics. | |
| • GPA: 6.7/7.0 | |
| Beijing Institute of Technology | 2010 - 2012 |
| Bachelor of Engineering | |
| • Major: Optical Information Science and Technology. | |
| • GPA: 4.0/4.0 | |
| | |
| Honors and Awards | |

| 2019 - 2020 | Postgraduate Research Scholarship |
|-------------|---|
| 2017 - 2019 | Australian Government Research Training Program Scholarship |
| 2016 - 2017 | Australian Postgraduate Award |
| | Higher Degree By Research (HDR) Supplementary Scholarship |
| 2015 - 2016 | HDR Fee Remission Merit Scholarship |
| | ANU PhD Scholarship |
| 2014 - 2014 | Outstanding Graduates with First Class Honors |
| 2012 - 2014 | ANU CECS Undergraduate International Scholarship |
| 2012 - 2012 | National Scholarship (top 0.2%) |
| 2010 - 2011 | University First Prize scholarship (top 1%) |

Teaching experience

| Australia National University Academic Staff | 2016-2018 |
|---|-----------|
| • Fibre Optic Communications Systems Course | |
| • Photonic Sensing Systems Course | |
| Beihang University | 2012-2012 |

 $Lab\ assistant$

Industry experience

Liquid Instruments

2019 - Present

Test and QA Engineer

Beijing SWT Science and Technology Co

2012 - 2013

Trainee engineer

Major responsibilities and roles

QA/QC Test Development

2019 - 2021

Create the test plan for the manufacturing line; identify quality assurance process; develop automation tests to verify the product functionalities with respect to the FPGA (including the DDR, Bluetooth, EMAC, eMMC, USB, QSPI, JTAG, WiFi, SFP, SATA, I2C/SPI continuity and etc); generate test documents and specification of the product.

Hardware Design

2019 - 2021

Develop hardware circuitry that meets certain functionalities and requirements; circuitry simulations and validations; PCB review.

Project Coordinator

2019 - 2021

Contact and communicate with business partners; involved with project plans and schedules.

Optical device testing

2012 - 2013

Optical waveguide simulation and design; optical fibre coupler testing.

Publication and Talks

Polarization Impedance Matching Cavity Enhanced Laser Absorption Spectroscopy Y. J. Guan, C. P. Bandutunga, J. Dong, T. T. Lam, R. Fleddermann, M. B. Gray, and J. H. Chow. *Manuscript Submitted to Optics Express*, 2021

Quantum Noise Limited Trace Gas Cavity Enhanced Polarization Spectroscopy

Y. J. Guan, J. Dong, C. P. Bandutunga, R. Fleddermann, T. T. Lam, M. B. Gray, and J. H. Chow. Light, Energy and the Environment 2018 (E2, FTS, HISE, SOLAR, SSL), OSA Technical Digest (Optical Society of America, 2018), paper EW3A.8.

Cavity Enhanced Polarization Impedance Matching Spectroscopy

J. Dong, T. T. Lam, R. Fleddermann, Y. Guan, C. P. Bandutunga, D. E. McClelland, M. B. Gray, and J. H. Chow

Light, Energy and the Environment 2015, OSA Technical Digest (Optical Society of America, 2015), paper ETh2A.2.

Cavity Polarization Mode Impedance Matching Spectroscopy

Y. J. Guan, J. Dong, T. T. Lam, R. Fleddermann, C. P. Bandutunga, D. E. McClelland, M. B. Gray, and J. H. Chow.

Oral Presentation at The Australian and New Zealand Conference on Optics and Photonics (ANZCOP) 2017

Double Pass Cavity Enhanced Absorption Measurement with Scattering Minimisation Y. J. Guan, C. P. Bandutunga, J. Dong, R. Fleddermann, M. B. Gray, T. T. Lam, and J. H. Chow. Oral Presentation at The Australian and New Zealand Conference on Optics and Photonics (ANZCOP) 2015

References

Available upon request